<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_u4h_mwf_qs">
 <title>Preview and Edit the Pipeline</title>
 <shortdesc>The extended tutorial is almost done, so let's use data preview to see how stages
    transform data. While in data preview, we'll make some configuration changes and edit preview
    data for testing. </shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p>To preview the pipeline, click the preview icon: <image
        href="../Graphics/icon-ConfigDataPreview.png" id="image_iqz_1hg_qs" scale="70"/>.</p>
  <p>You can explore how each stage transforms data by selecting the stage and reviewing the input
   and output records in the Preview panel. Listed here are some details to note:<dl>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>Field Masker</dt>
          <dd>Let's see how the Field Masker masks credit card numbers and change the mask type. </dd>
     <dd>To see how the Field Masker masks credit card numbers: <ol id="ol_ht2_5lg_qs">
       <li>Select the Field Masker in the canvas, and then expand the first input and output
        record.</li>
       <li>Scroll down and note that index 20 is highlighted, indicating a change.</li>
       <li> Expand index 20 for the input and output data. Notice how all digits except the last 4
        are masked. </li>
      </ol></dd>
     <dd>Say we want to change the mask type to mask the whole credit card number. To review the
            stage configuration and try a different option:<ol id="ol_vvw_wlg_qs">
              <li>On the left side of the Preview panel, select the <uicontrol>Stage
                  Configuration</uicontrol> icon: <image href="../Graphics/icon_PrevStageConfig.png"
                  id="image_xnl_lmg_qs" scale="85"/>.<p>You might need to scroll up to the top of
                  the panel.</p></li>
              <li>Click the <uicontrol>Mask</uicontrol> tab.</li>
              <li>Change the <uicontrol>Mask Type</uicontrol> to <uicontrol>Variable
                  Length</uicontrol> to mask all numbers while showing how many numbers there are in
                the data. </li>
              <li>To view the data with this change, click the <uicontrol>Run with
                  Changes</uicontrol> icon. <draft-comment author="Loretta">Check if there's a New
                  Data/Old data option later?</draft-comment></li>
              <li>In the canvas, select the <uicontrol>Field Masker</uicontrol> processor and if the
                Preview panel displays the stage configuration, select the
                  <uicontrol>Records</uicontrol> tab to view the preview records. </li>
              <li> Expand an output record, expand index 20, and notice how the entire number is now
                masked. </li>
            </ol></dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>Second Jython Evaluator</dt>
     <dd>The second Jython Evaluator flattens the delimited data. Let's take a look:<ul
              id="ul_qvt_lmm_qs">
              <li>Select the <uicontrol>second Jython Evaluator</uicontrol> and expand the first
                input and output record. <p>Notice how the input record is a list of maps and the
                  output record has been flattened to the following structure: &lt;field name>:
                  &lt;value>. Isn't that great? </p></li>
            </ul></dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>Field Converter</dt>
     <dd>The Field Converter changes the data type of a few fields. We'll take a look at that stage
            and try changing stage configuration. <ol id="ol_ajx_pmm_qs">
              <li>To move the preview focus to the Field Converter, you can click the
                  <uicontrol>Next Stage</uicontrol> icon instead of selecting the stage in the
                  pipeline.<p>You might notice a red message that indicates the first record has an
                  unparsable date - it shows that the date data includes invalid characters at the
                  end. </p><p>So what happens to this bad record? It depends on how the stage is
                  configured. We used the default configuration, but let's see what that
                is.</p></li>
              <li>Click the <uicontrol>Stage Configuration</uicontrol> icon. Notice the
                  <uicontrol>On Record Error</uicontrol> property is set to <uicontrol>Send to
                  Error</uicontrol>. <p>This means error records are sent to the pipeline for error
                  handling. And you might recall we configured the pipeline to write all error
                  records to file. So with this configuration, the error record will be dropped from
                  the pipeline and written to file. </p><p>You can configure this property to stop
                  the pipeline on encountering an error record or to discard error records.</p></li>
              <li>To see how it looks when you discard errors, set <uicontrol>On Record
                  Error</uicontrol> to <uicontrol>Discard</uicontrol>. And then, click the
                  <uicontrol>Refresh Preview</uicontrol> icon.</li>
              <li>On the canvas, select the <uicontrol>Field Converter </uicontrol>stage, and then
                click the <uicontrol>Records</uicontrol> icon in the Preview panel. Notice the first
                record is discarded without notice of the error that occurred. </li>
              <li>We prefer to keep error records, so go back to the Stage Configuration tab and
                change <uicontrol>On Record Error</uicontrol> back to <uicontrol>Send to
                  Error</uicontrol>.</li>
            </ol></dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>Second Expression Evaluator</dt>
     <dd>The second Expression Evaluator manipulates data. Let's try editing the preview data:<ol
              id="ol_u54_mx3_rs">
              <li>Click the <uicontrol>Next Stage</uicontrol> icon or select the Expression
                Evaluator.</li>
              <li>If necessary, expand a couple input and output records. <p>Notice the fields
                  created by the stage, pickup_location and trip_location, are highlighted in
                  green.</p><p>Though it isn't necessary for these calculations, let's see how you
                  can edit preview data to test stage configuration.</p></li>
              <li>In the first input record - in the Input Data column, click on the Pickup Latitude
                  data,<uicontrol> 40.730068</uicontrol>, add a negative sign before the data, and
                hit <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol> or click outside the data.<p>The edited input data
                  becomes red to indicate a change. </p></li>
              <li>To test the change, click the <uicontrol>Run Preview with Changes</uicontrol>
                icon: <image href="../Graphics/icon_PreviewRerun.png" id="image_awt_jbj_rs"
                  scale="95"/>.<p>The <ph
                    conref="../Reusable_Content/ReusablePhrases.dita#concept_vhs_5tz_xp/pName-long"
                  /> runs the preview with the change. Notice the corresponding output record now
                  has -40.730068 for both pickup_latitude and pickup_location. </p><p><image
                    href="../Graphics/Tutorial-PreviewEditData.png" id="image_bgm_cfj_rs" scale="80"
                  /></p><p>You can see how this functionality might come in handy when you want to
                  test some cases that didn't come up in the preview data. </p></li>
              <li>To revert that change, click the <uicontrol>Revert Data Changes</uicontrol> icon:
                  <image href="../Graphics/icon_PrevRevertChanges.png" id="image_pnr_bfp_rs"
                  scale="95"/>.<p>This icon does not revert configuration changes. </p>
              </li>
            </ol></dd>
    </dlentry>
   </dl></p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
