<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--

    Copyright 2017 StreamSets Inc.

    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_u4h_mwf_qs">
 <title>Preview and Edit the Pipeline</title>
 <shortdesc>The extended tutorial is almost done, so let's use data preview to see how different
    stages transform data.  We'll make some configuration changes and do some testing by editing
    preview data.</shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p>To preview the pipeline, click the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> icon: <image
        href="../Graphics/icon_Preview.png" id="image_wvk_tpd_5s" scale="80"/>.</p>
  <p>You can explore how each stage transforms data by selecting the stage and reviewing the input
      and output records in the Preview panel. Let's focus on the following stages:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Field Masker</dt>
          <dd>Let's see how the Field Masker masks credit card numbers and change the mask that the
            stage uses.</dd>
          <dd>To see how the Field Masker masks credit card numbers: <ol id="ol_ht2_5lg_qs">
              <li>Select the Field Masker in the canvas, and then expand the first input and output
                record.</li>
              <li>Scroll down and note that the credit_card field is highlighted. This indicates the
                stage changed data in the field.</li>
              <li>Notice how all digits except the last four are masked. We did this by using the
                Regular Expression mask type and revealing the second group in the regex.</li>
            </ol></dd>
          <dd><image href="../Graphics/Tutorial-PreviewFMasker.png" id="image_u3z_gdl_5s" scale="50"
            /></dd>
          <dd>Say we want to mask the whole credit card number. To review the stage configuration
            and try a different option:<ol id="ol_vvw_wlg_qs">
              <li>Scroll up to the top of the Preview panel. Then, on the left, select the
                  <uicontrol>Stage Configuration</uicontrol> icon: <image
                  href="../Graphics/icon_PrevStageConfig.png" id="image_xnl_lmg_qs" scale="85"
                />.</li>
              <li>Click the <uicontrol>Mask</uicontrol> tab.</li>
              <li>Change the <uicontrol>Mask Type</uicontrol> to <uicontrol>Variable
                  Length</uicontrol> to mask all numbers while showing how many numbers there are in
                the data. </li>
              <li>To view the results of this change, click the <uicontrol>Run with
                  Changes</uicontrol> icon: <image href="../Graphics/icon_PreviewRerun.png"
                  scale="95" id="image_apd_ztd_5s"/>.</li>
              <li>In the Preview panel, select the <uicontrol>Records</uicontrol> tab to view the
                updated preview records: <image href="../Graphics/icon_PrevRecords.png"
                  id="image_m3w_sdl_5s" scale="75"/>.</li>
              <li> Expand an output record, and notice how the entire credit card number is now
                    masked:<p><image href="../Graphics/Tutorial-PreviewFMasker2.png"
                    id="image_chj_c2l_5s" scale="50"/></p></li>
            </ol></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Field Type Converter</dt>
          <dd>The Field Type Converter changes the data type of a few fields. We'll take a look at
            that stage and try changing stage configuration. <ol id="ol_ajx_pmm_qs">
              <li>Instead of selecting the Field Type Converter in the pipeline, click the
                  <uicontrol>Next Stage</uicontrol> icon: <image
                  href="../Graphics/icon_PrevNextStage.png" id="image_i41_ssd_5s"/> and select
                  <uicontrol>Field Type Converter</uicontrol>.<p>You might notice a red message that
                  indicates the first record has an unparsable date - it shows that the date data
                  includes invalid characters at the end. </p><p>So what happens to this bad record?
                  It depends on how the stage is configured. We used the default configuration, but
                  let's see what that is.</p></li>
              <li>On the left side of the panel, click the <uicontrol>Stage
                  Configuration</uicontrol> icon: <image href="../Graphics/icon_PrevStageConfig.png"
                  id="image_ehm_svw_15" scale="80"/>. Notice the <uicontrol>On Record
                  Error</uicontrol> property is set to <uicontrol>Send to Error</uicontrol>. <p>This
                  means error records are sent to the pipeline for error handling. We configured the
                  pipeline to write all error records to file, so error records from this stage are
                  written to file. </p><p>You can configure this property to stop the pipeline on
                  encountering an error record or to discard error records.</p></li>
              <li>To see how it looks when you discard errors, set <uicontrol>On Record
                  Error</uicontrol> to <uicontrol>Discard</uicontrol>, and then click the
                  <uicontrol>Run with Changes</uicontrol> icon.</li>
              <li>In the Preview panel, click the <uicontrol>Records</uicontrol> icon. <p>Notice the
                  first record is discarded without notice of the error that occurred. </p></li>
              <li>We prefer to keep error records, so go back to the Stage Configuration tab and
                change <uicontrol>On Record Error</uicontrol> back to <uicontrol>Send to
                  Error</uicontrol>.</li>
            </ol></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Second Expression Evaluator</dt>
          <dd>The second Expression Evaluator manipulates data. Let's try editing the preview
              data:<ol id="ol_u54_mx3_rs">
              <li>Click the <uicontrol>Next Stage</uicontrol> icon or select the Expression
                Evaluator.</li>
              <li>Click the <uicontrol>Records</uicontrol> icon and expand the first input and
                output record. <p>Notice the fields created by the stage - dropoff_location,
                  pickup_location and trip_revenue - are highlighted in green.</p><p>Though it isn't
                  necessary for these calculations, let's see how you can edit preview data to test
                  stage configuration:</p></li>
              <li>In the first input record, in the Input Data column, click on the Pickup Latitude
                  data,<uicontrol> 40.730068</uicontrol>, add a negative sign before the data. Hit
                  <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol> or click outside the data.<p>As shown below, the
                  edited input data becomes red to indicate a change. </p></li>
              <li>To test the change, click the <uicontrol>Run with Changes</uicontrol> icon.<p>The
                    <ph
                    conref="../Reusable_Content/ReusablePhrases.dita#concept_vhs_5tz_xp/pName-long"
                  /> runs the preview with the change. Notice the corresponding output record now
                  has -40.730068 for both pickup_latitude and pickup_location. </p><p><image
                    href="../Graphics/Tutorial-PreviewEditData.png" id="image_bgm_cfj_rs" scale="50"
                  /></p><p>You can see how this functionality might come in handy when you want to
                  test some cases that didn't come up in the preview data. </p></li>
              <li>To revert that change, click the <uicontrol>Revert Data Changes</uicontrol> icon:
                  <image href="../Graphics/icon_PrevRevertChanges.png" id="image_pnr_bfp_rs"
                  scale="95"/>.<p>This icon reverts changes to preview data.
                    </p><note><uicontrol>Revert Data Changes</uicontrol> does not revert changes to
                  stage or pipeline configuration. Manually revert configuration changes that you
                  don't want to keep, as we did earlier in the tutorial. </note></li>
            </ol></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <p>When you're done exploring the preview data, click <uicontrol>Close Preview</uicontrol>.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
