<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--

    Copyright 2017 StreamSets Inc.

    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA General Task//EN" "generalTask.dtd">
<task id="task_br5_rzq_ks">
    <title>Route Data with the Stream Selector</title>
    <shortdesc>To route data to different streams for processing, we use the Stream Selector
        processor.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <context><p>The Stream Selector routes data to different streams based on user-defined
                conditions. Any data not captured by a user-defined condition routes to the default
                stream.</p><p>We'll route credit card transactions to a credit card stream for
                processing. All other transactions will go to the default stream.</p><p>We'll also
                define a required field to drop records with no payment type. When you define a
                required field, a record must include data for the specified field to enter the
                stage. Records that don't include data in required fields are sent to the pipeline
                for error handling. If you configured the pipeline to write to file, that's where
                error records go. </p>To represent data in a field, we use the
                <codeph>record:value</codeph> function. This returns field values associated with
            the field.<p>To capture records with credit card payments, use the following condition:
                <codeblock>${record:value('/payment_type') == 'CRD'}</codeblock></p><p>Note that we
                enclose expressions in a dollar sign and curly brackets. You can use single or
                double quotation marks around strings. For more information about the expression
                language, see <xref
                    href="../Expression_Language/ExpressionLanguage_overview.dita#concept_p54_4kl_vq"
                />.</p></context>
        <steps id="steps_xhx_3rk_ls">
            <step>
                <cmd>From the Pipeline Creation Help Bar, click <menucascade>
                        <uicontrol>Select Processor to Connect</uicontrol>
                        <uicontrol>Stream Selector</uicontrol>
                    </menucascade>. Or, in the stage library, select the <uicontrol>Stream
                        Selector</uicontrol> processor (<image
                        href="../Graphics/Tutorial_SSelector_icon.png" id="image_rt1_3m1_mt"
                        scale="65"/>) and connect the Directory origin to it. </cmd>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>On the <wintitle>General</wintitle> tab, click in the <uicontrol>Required
                        Fields</uicontrol> text box. </cmd>
                <info>A list of available fields displays because you already performed data
                    preview. It also displays when the pipeline is valid for data preview. </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>To discard records with no payment type information, select the following
                    field: <uicontrol>/payment_type</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <info>If a list does not appear, you can manually enter the field path:
                    /payment_type.</info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>To configure the Stream Selector condition, click the
                        <uicontrol>Conditions</uicontrol> tab.</cmd>
                <info>A condition for the default stream displays. The default stream represents any
                    records not captured by other conditions.</info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> icon: <image
                        href="../Graphics/icon_ConfigAddIcon.png" id="image_snw_l5p_15" scale="50"
                    />.</cmd>
                <info>A condition text box displays in the Property panel, and the corresponding
                    output location appears on the stage in the canvas.</info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>The following condition captures records where a credit card is used for
                    payment. You can copy and paste the expression, but try typing it in to see how
                    the expression completion feature helps you select the function and ensure valid
                    syntax.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock>${record:value('/payment_type') == 'CRD'}</codeblock>
                </info>
                <info>All records that match this condition pass to the first output stream. All
                    other records are captured by the default condition and passed through the
                    second output stream.</info>
            </step>
        </steps>
        <result>The Stream Selector should look like this:<p><image
                    href="../Graphics/Tutorial-StreamSelector.png" id="image_t1s_png_4s" scale="60"
                /></p></result>
    </taskbody>
</task>
