<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Copyright 2017 StreamSets Inc.

  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  
      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
      
  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_alb_b3y_cbb">
 <title>Simple and Bulk Edit Mode</title>
 <conbody>
        <p><indexterm>bulk edit mode<indexterm>description</indexterm></indexterm><indexterm>simple
                edit mode<indexterm>description</indexterm></indexterm>Some pipeline and pipeline
            stage properties include an Add icon (<image href="../Graphics/icon_ConfigAddIcon.png"
                scale="50" id="image_wy5_3ly_cbb"/>) where you add additional configurations. You
            can add the configurations in simple or bulk edit mode. By default, each property uses
            simple edit mode. </p>
  <p>For example, in the Expression Evaluator, you can click the Add icon in simple edit mode to add
            multiple expressions to the processor. The stage displays text boxes for you to enter
            configuration values, as follows:</p>
        <p><image href="../Graphics/SimpleEditMode.png" scale="70" id="image_shd_mjy_cbb"/></p>
        <p>Or, you can switch to bulk edit mode to enter a list of configurations in JSON format,
            for example:</p>
        <p><image href="../Graphics/BulkEditMode.png" scale="70" id="image_a1y_lky_cbb"/></p>
        <p>When you switch to bulk edit mode, Data Collector displays the correct field names and
            any values that you entered in simple edit mode. Modify the values, but be sure not to
            modify the field names. If you modify the field names by mistake, Data Collector
            displays a validation error message.</p>
        <p>In bulk edit mode, you can add additional configurations by entering text in JSON format.
            Or, you can click the Add icon to add another configuration with empty values and then
            enter the values in the JSON text.</p>
        <p>Bulk edit mode can be particularly useful when you have a large number of configurations
            to enter. For example, you might want to configure the OPC UA Client origin to subscribe
            to hundreds of nodes in an OPC UA server. In this case, use the Add icon to add one node
            configuration. Then, switch to bulk edit mode and copy the JSON text for that node
            configuration into a text file. Use the same format and required field names to
            configure additional nodes in the text file. Then simply copy the node configurations
            from the JSON text file into bulk edit mode, rather than individually adding each node
            with the Add icon. </p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
