<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--

    Copyright 2017 StreamSets Inc.

    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_xr4_zt3_3r">
 <title>Default Stream</title>
 <shortdesc>The default stream captures records that do not match user-defined conditions. Use the
  default stream to manage unmatched records. </shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p><indexterm>Stream Selector processor<indexterm>default
    stream</indexterm></indexterm><indexterm>default stream<indexterm>Stream
    Selector</indexterm></indexterm>When you configure the Stream Selector, you connect each stream
   to a branch in the pipeline. The default stream is the last stream in the stage.</p>
  <p>You can configure the branch for the default stream to perform additional processing or to
   write directly to a destination. If you do not need the records in the default stream, you can
   connect the stream to a Trash destination.</p>
  <p>For example, the following image shows the conditions for a Stream Selector that processes
   tweeted data:</p>
  <p><image href="../Graphics/StreamSelector-config.png" id="image_tgw_w2j_3r"/></p>
  <p>The first condition evaluates for records that have been deleted. The second condition
   evaluates for records flagged as sensitive. The third default condition captures all remaining
   records.</p>
  <p>The following image shows the Stream Selector in the pipeline: </p>
  <p>
   <image href="../Graphics/StreamSelector-Pipeline.png" id="image_gyn_nps_gr" scale="90"/></p>
  <p>The first stream passes deleted tweets to the Deleted Tweets destination. The second stream
   passes new tweets with sensitive language to a Field Masker to mask the inappropriate text. The
   third stream, the default stream, passes all remaining tweets directly to the New Tweets
   destination. </p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
