<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  
      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
      
  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_rs5_hjj_tw">
    <title>Oracle CDC Client</title>
    <conbody>
        <p><indexterm>origins<indexterm>Oracle CDC Client</indexterm></indexterm><indexterm>Oracle
                CDC Client origin<indexterm>overview</indexterm></indexterm>The Oracle CDC Client
            processes change data capture (CDC) information provided by Oracle LogMiner redo logs.
            The Oracle CDC Client origin produces records with a map of fields and record header
            attributes with CDC information. Use Oracle CDC Client to process data from Oracle
            version 12c.</p>
        <p>When needed, you can use a separate pipeline with the JDBC Consumer origin to read
            existing data before you start a pipeline with Oracle CDC Client.</p>
        <p>The Oracle CDC Client origin can create records for insert, update, select-for-update,
            and delete operations for one or more tables in a database. You can select the
            operations that you want to use.</p>
        <p>
            <note>To use Oracle CDC Client, you must enable LogMiner for the database that you want
                to use and complete the necessary prerequisite tasks. The origin uses JDBC to access
                the database.</note>
        </p>
        <p>When you configure Oracle CDC Client, you configure change data capture details, such as
            the database and tables to read from, how to read the initial change, the dictionary
            source location, and the operations to include. </p>
        <p>You also specify JDBC connection information and user credentials. If the database was
            created in a pluggable database, state the pluggable database name. You can configure
            custom properties that the driver requires.</p>
        <p>
            <ph
                conref="../Reusable_Content/ReusablePhrases.dita#concept_vhs_5tz_xp/ph-JDBC-legacyInfo"
            /></p>
    </conbody>
</concept>
