<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  
      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
      
  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_av4_pnm_z1b">
 <title>Script Configuration</title>
 <conbody>
  <p><indexterm>Shell executor<indexterm>script configuration</indexterm></indexterm>When
            configuring a shell script for the Shell executor, note the following details:<ol
                id="ol_kl1_dpm_z1b">
                <li>When you configure the shell script, ensure that the script returns zero (0) to
                    indicate successful execution. For example, in a bash script, you can use "exit
                    0" to return the required zero value.<p>A script that does not return zero might
                        run successfully when tested on the command line, but will generate errors
                        when used by the Shell executor in a pipeline. </p></li>
                <li>You cannot use expressions directly in the shell script. To use <ph
                        conref="../Reusable_Content/ReusablePhrases.dita#concept_vhs_5tz_xp/pName-long"
                    /> expressions in a script: <ul id="ul_g2y_rxm_z1b">
                        <li>Use the Environment Variables property in the stage to declare
                            environment variables for the script. Create an environment variable for
                            each expression that you want to use. </li>
                        <li>Use the environment variables as needed in the script. </li>
                    </ul><p>For example, say you want to perform an action on a file that was closed
                        by a Hadoop FS destination - one that you cannot perform with the HDFS File
                        Metadata executor. And you want to use the filepath field in the event
                        record to specify the absolute path to the closed file. </p><p>So you can
                        define a filepath environment variable using the following expression:
                            <codeph>${record:value('/filepath')}</codeph> as shown below, then use
                        the filepath environment variable in the script:</p><p><image
                            href="../Graphics/Shell-EnvVariables.png" id="image_n1r_wdn_z1b"
                            scale="65"/></p></li>
            </ol></p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
