<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  
      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
      
  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_hh4_sgx_j1b">
 <title>Working with Field Attributes</title>
 <conbody>
  <p><indexterm>field attributes<indexterm>working with</indexterm></indexterm>Like record header
            attributes, you can use the Expression Evaluator or any scripting processor to create or
            update field attributes. For example, when processing Avro data, origins place the
            precision and scale information for Decimal data into field attributes. If you want to
            increase those values before writing them to the destination system, you can use the
            Expression Evaluator or any scripting processor to set the attribute value.</p>
        <p>Field attributes are string values. You can also use
                <codeph>record:fieldAttribute</codeph> functions in any expression to include
            attribute values in calculations. </p>
        <p>
            <note type="important">Field attributes do not have field paths. When using an attribute
                in an expression, use just the attribute name surrounded by quotation marks after
                specifying the path to the associated field, as
                follows:<codeblock> ${record:fieldAttribute(&lt;path to the field>,'&lt;attribute name>')}</codeblock></note>
        </p>
        <p>For example, say you are processing Avro data as part of the <xref
                href="../Hive_Drift_Solution/HiveDrift-Overview.dita#concept_phk_bdf_2w">Drift
                Synchronization Solution for Hive</xref>. All Decimal fields include automatically
            generated precision and scale field attributes. Before passing the data to the Hive
            Metadata processor, you want to create a new Price Decimal field based on the existing
            cost data. </p>
        <p>The following Expression Evaluator creates the Price field and defines the precision and
            scale field attributes based on the existing Cost precision and scale. </p>
        <p><image href="../Graphics/FieldAtts-ExpressionEval.png" id="image_mxb_wkx_j1b" scale="60"
            /></p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
